Adam Behnke

Dev with 30+ years experience across a variety of industries.

Ransom Canyon, TX 79366 adambehnke@gmail.com +1 806 329 0312

Heavy web, hardware, and telco experience. Comfortable with reverse-engineering and inventing protocols and APIs, protocol analyzers, and never giving up until it works.

Have coded in many scripting and compiled languages and haven't found a language yet within which I cannot work, but most comfortable in C-derived syntax.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Centrifuge, LLC - Ransom Canyon, TX June 2020 to Present

Developer, Architect, Engineer for an assortment of projects.

General technologist with deep experience in web and telco.

Successfully deployed the following:

- https://www.ecardsystems.com High-volume Wordpress Woocommerce site
- https://www.sce.com Drupal 8 migration and build; wrote pipeline deployments in BB, GL; Acquia BLT; custom Behat testing
- Globe Telecom (https://www.globe.com.ph/) Big Data SMS and locative data collection suite using Perl, PHP, C, MongoDB, Percona (My/MariaDB), custom hardware (FPGAs) and interconnect APIs, Tableau reporting, MapTiler GIS integration
- Vodacom Mozambique (https://www.vm.co.mz/) Location reporting and fraud-busting platform (proximity-based transaction validation for M-Pesa) using Perl, PHP, C, MariaDB

Senior Application Developer

Accella, LLC - Ransom Canyon, TX August 2011 to June 2020

Lead developer, architect, and administrator for numerous projects:

- Drupal 8/9: https://www.cumanagement.com, https://avalere.com, https://www.cues.org, https://hcar.org, https://www.thebcat.com
- Drupal 7: https://www.lapl.org, https://www.archives.gov, https://www.obamalibrary.gov, https://www.crainsdetroit.com, https://www.iwanamaker.com
- Parker Fitting Finder (Obj-C): https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/parker-fitting-finder/id573942435
- SME: Drupal 5/6/7/8/9, PHP, MySQL (Maria, Percona), Perl 5, JS, CSS, Wordpress CLI / custom plugins, Linux CLI dev and admin, AWS, Pantheon, Acquia BLT, CI/CD (Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket Pipelines), SOLR, Git, REST/CRUD, JIRA, Docker

- Other: Mongo, PgSQL, C#, Java, Laravel, Ruby (Rails), React.js, Node, Symfony, Python, Hardware Integration, PHPUnit, Behat
- Drupal expert (custom modules/themes, features, composer, migrations, drush, custom web services)

Senior Software Engineer

GBSD Technologies, Inc January 2005 to June 2011

- Responsible for architecture, development, and implementation of all software worldwide.
- Relocated to South Africa in 2009 for business development and to oversee implementation of LBS/LDS.
- Granted US Patent 6,859,172 for AOA system.
- Granted US Patent 8,238,941 and 8,521,191 for non-GPS cellular location.
- Designed and developed software (SAS, SMLC, GMLC, A-GPS, CAML, SIGTRAN, RiskUI, Anti-Wangiri, Anti-Fraud) certified by Motorola, ALU, NSN, Huawei, and Nortel.
- SME: protocol analysis / creation, wire-level communication, high-TPS, big data, 3GPP standards, ASN.1
- Managed technical team in South Africa for on-site support.
- See: http://gbsdtech.com/wpweb and https://patents.justia.com/inventor/adam-v-behnke
- Heavy telco protocol stack engineering and development (TCP/UDP/SS7/SIGTRAN/Diameter), custom API development (C/Perl), Big Data (Percona/My/MariaDB/MongoDB), web (Perl/CGI/Drupal 5/6/7), automation, replication, reporting (Tableau)
- Foundry Management Software (integrated with Windows-based Spectrometer for burn stats), pattern organization, time management using Perl, PHP, MySQL, custom UDP APIs, Drupal 5/6/7
- Machine Shop Management Software (custom barcoding with reader integration, barcode reader daemon monitoring, time management, historical reporting / comparison) using Perl, PHP, MySQL, custom UDP APIs, Drupal 5/6/7
- Robotic G-Code Builder (generates G-Code for robotic arm control synchronized with CAD mill monitored by predictive amperage draw daemon) using Perl, PHP, MySQL, custom UDP APIs, Drupal 5/6/7
- See https://patents.justia.com/search?q=navarro+IP%2C+LLC+kirk+williamson and https://patents.justia.com/patent/20190255668

IT Analyst / Software Developer

Cingular (AT&T) Wireless 2000 to 2004

- Managed a 2000+ system network
- Built numerous automated processes and systems in Perl/CGI and MSSQL.
- Lead programmer and architect for the Symposium Management Solution, a system that passively collects data from all Cingular call center PBXs, aggregates information, and allows nationwide reporting of statistics via a web interface. Patent filed by Cingular as #20060203991. Coded in Perl/CGI and MSSQL.

Lead Network Engineer

Western Computer Supply Company (WCSC) - Lubbock, TX 1996 to 2000

Managed the technology of a local ISP, built computers, websites, and managed databases.

Freelance Developer

Centrifuge, LLC - Lubbock County, TX 1988 to 1996

Worked on a variety business systems.

Token-ring networks, Novell systems, MS-DOS / WindowsNT / Windows 3.1 administration and configuration, building and upgrading hardware.

Custom scripting and programming, mostly in shell, Perl, C, Pascal.

Programmer

Lockheed Martin - Lubbock, TX May 1988 to August 1988

Worked in the QA/QAE division shell programming MS-DOS PC-ATs.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Language

Texas Tech University - Lubbock, TX 2001

Master's in Theology

University of Dallas - Irving, TX

Skills

- Git
- JavaScript
- Linux
- · Microsoft SQL Server
- MySQL
- APIs
- AWS
- C/C++
- SQL
- HTML5
- PHP
- SDLC
- Shell Scripting
- REST
- Node.js
- Unit Testing
- Agile
- XML
- CSS
- GitHub
- Scrum

- Docker
- Test Cases
- Perl (10+ years)
- Big data (10+ years)
- Jira
- Scripting
- Software Development
- Application Development
- Web Development
- Operating Systems
- UNIX
- Software Deployment
- Python
- User Interface (UI)
- CI/CD
- Web Services
- VMWare
- Ubuntu
- Virtualization
- E-commerce
- Test automation
- DevOps
- PostgreSQL
- BSD
- Relational databases
- Software troubleshooting
- System architecture
- Performance tuning
- Debian
- AJAX
- jQuery
- CentOS
- LAMP stack
- Apache
- Redis
- Full-stack development
- Content management systems
- TCP/IP

Languages

- English Expert
- German Fluent
- Spanish Intermediate

Links

https://avalere.com

https://dev.charmcityconcierge.com

https://hcar.org

https://hcarcares.org

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/parker-fitting-finder/id573942435

https://www.archives.gov

https://www.crainsdetroit.com

https://www.cues.org

https://www.cumanagement.com

https://www.iwanamaker.com

https://www.lapl.org

https://www.obamalibrary.gov

https://www.thebcat.com

Assessments

Analyzing Data — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Project Timeline Management — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Prioritizing and allocating time to effectively achieve project deliverables

Full results: Highly Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Patents

System and method for locating a mobile phone (#6859172)

https://patents.justia.com/patent/6859172

February 2005

System and method for determining a location for a mobile device (#8238941)

https://patents.justia.com/patent/8238941

August 2012

System and method for determining a location for a mobile device (#8521191)

https://patents.justia.com/patent/8521191

August 2013